you say
你说
Was it really Feng Qi who bandaged Jiang Zhaoguo?
Was it really Feng Qi who bandaged Jiang Zhaoguo?
I do not know then
那时我不知道
Does anyone know how Feng Qi was bandaged?
有谁知道冯琪是怎么包扎的吗？
Then he conspired with Jiang Zhaoguo
然后又与蒋兆国密谋
He was framed together
他被陷害在一起
I would like to ask Mr. Jiang to do me a favor
我想请江先生帮我一个忙
you say
你说
I think he will definitely agree
我想他肯定会同意的
That's it
就是这样
Can Mr. Jiang
Can Mr. Jiang
When being interviewed by reporters
接受记者采访时
Use the figure-eight spiral method
使用8字形螺旋法
bandage his injured right arm
包扎他受伤的右臂
This is the bandaging process
这是包扎过程
And when the photo was published in the newspaper
当这张照片刊登在报纸上时
Be sure to take a good look at his bandaged right arm
一定要仔细看看他缠着绷带的右臂
What a strange request
多么奇怪的要求
But for you
但对于你来说
It doesn't seem surprising
似乎并不奇怪
Wife
妻子
You’ve read too much wild history
你读了太多狂野的历史
How could there be so much conspiracy?
怎么会有这么多阴谋？
At most, God opens his eyes
最多是上帝睁开眼睛
Think Feng Qi has done many evil things
认为风起做了很多坏事
Plus my wisdom root, right?
再加上我的智慧根吧？
Was woken up all of a sudden
突然被惊醒
Discovered this detail about him
发现了这个关于他的细节
Anyway, in one sentence
无论如何，一句话
It’s Feng Qi who deserves to be unlucky
活该倒霉的是冯琪
I think so too
我也这么认为
Came back from get off work
下班回来
You mean this big horse spoon?
你是说这个大马勺吗？
This note I got
我收到的这张纸条
It was really the information that Feng Qi passed on to Juntong.
确实是风起传递给军统的信息。
It's all Feng Qi's handwriting
都是冯起的手笔
It definitely can’t be fake
绝对不可能是假的
Could it be that someone framed him?
难道是有人陷害他？
he is so smart
他很聪明
Who could frame him?
谁能陷害他？
That Feng Qi who doubted you
那个怀疑你的风起
I found someone to follow him
我找到一个人跟踪他
He went to Nanjing Pukou Station
他去南京浦口站
Looking for a vendor selling sachets
寻找卖香包的商贩
Could it be that the sachet I lost is in Feng Qi’s hand?
难道我丢失的香囊就在风起手里？
What's wrong? There's trouble.
怎么了？有麻烦了。
Who is following him?
谁在跟踪他？
My name is Li Youtian
我叫李友田
Are you smart enough?
你够聪明吗？
no problem
没问题
I want him to do something for me
我想让他为我做点什么
Could it be this Li Youtian?
难道是这个李幼田？
Trick Feng Qi into writing something
骗封奇写东西
Words with completely different meanings
含义完全不同的词
Then select a few words and cut them out
然后选几个字剪掉
Where is Feng Qi framed?
冯琪被陷害去哪儿了？
Let me say
让我说
You write it
你写吧
I guarantee that after Li Youtian arrives in Shanghai
我保证李友田到上海后
personal safety
人身安全
Promise to help Li Youtian
答应帮助李又田
Bought Hong Xiang Ji’s three-yellow chicken
买了红香记的三黄鸡
Fuyunzhai’s bean paste cake
福云斋的豆沙糕
Reimburse all travel expenses
报销所有差旅费用
And the cost of eating in restaurants
以及在餐馆吃饭的费用
I said you have read too many detective novels, right?
我说你侦探小说看太多了吧？
Who would put so much thought into it?
谁会花这么多心思？
Frame him
陷害他
That makes sense
这就说得通了
Anyway, it’s Feng Qi
不管怎样，都是冯琪
Deserve bad luck
运气不好是罪有应得
right
正确的
Let's go
我们走吧
I really don’t understand you very well
我真的不太了解你
Say you're a traitor who's messing around
说你是胡闹的叛徒
Sometimes you are quite brave
有时候你真的很勇敢
Not only brave but also thoughtful
不仅勇敢而且有思想
I don't even know your beliefs
我什至不知道你的信仰
what exactly is it
到底是什么
my faith
我的信仰
That is
那是
i love
我爱
And what I love
以及我所爱的
what do you love
你爱什么
money
钱
And home
还有家
Let's go home
我们回家吧
Lao Luo, look for me
老罗，找我吧
Come, come, come
怎样怎样怎样
What does it smell like to you?
你觉得它是什么味道？
Zhao An is here
赵安来了
Yeah
是的
He is now responsible for raising horses
他现在负责养马
so
所以
Horse shit taste
马屎味
Such a great taste
这么好的味道
Are you still in the mood to draw?
你还有心情画画吗？
Just because of the smell of horse manure
只因马粪味
I'm inspired
我受到启发
Look at the horse picture
看马图片
abnormal
异常
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Handover
交出
His future trading group three
他未来的交易组三
The work is mine
工作是我的
You're responsible for part of it
你要承担一部分责任
That won't work
那不行
What should I do with the general affairs department?
总务部该怎么办？
Chief of the General Affairs Section, you are in charge.
总务科科长，您负责吧。
He is just handing over the work to me temporarily.
他只是暂时把工作交给我。
But I hate the word "temporary" very much
但我非常讨厌“暂时”这个词
do you understand
你明白吗
clear
清除
And you
你呢
I'll double your salary
我会给你双倍工资
As for extra money, oil and water, etc.
至于额外的钱、油、水等等。
It depends on your own ability
这取决于你自己的能力
Where are Zhao An's people?
赵安的人呢？
Basically, everyone is sitting on the bench.
基本上每个人都坐在板凳上。
I'll leave everything that can be used to Damashio.
能用的东西我都会留给魂师。
You finally got ahead
你终于领先了
Where is my younger brother?
我的弟弟在哪里？
I also had some soup to drink.
我还喝了一些汤。
Got a car for you
为你有一辆车
I'll drive your wife to work from now on
从现在起我开车送你老婆去上班
No need, I have a motorcycle
不用了，我有摩托车
hold
抓住
Thank you bro
谢啦兄弟
By the way, let me ask you something.
顺便问一下，我问你一件事。
Did Zuo Shuangtao come by train?
左双涛是坐火车来的吗？
what does it mean
这是什么意思
Lao Luo
Lao Luo
look at you
看着你
Feng Qi kidnapped Kimura
风起绑架了木村
Such a big thing
这么大的事
I have to write an inspection report
我得写一份检查报告
Talk about doubts
说说疑惑
Otherwise it can
否则可以
can you understand me
你能听懂我说话吗
I asked her last night
我昨晚问她
She said that when she was working in Wuhan
她说，她在武汉工作时
There is a man who likes her
有一个男人喜欢她
Do you know where she went to school in Nanjing?
你知道她在南京哪里上学吗？
I bought her a Yunjin sachet
我给她买了一个云锦香包
Although she doesn't like that man
虽然她不喜欢那个男人
But she likes this sachet very much
不过她很喜欢这个香包
Just left it
刚留下的
That's it
就是这样
Then when Zhao An asked her
然后当赵安问她的时候
Why didn't she tell the truth?
她为什么不说实话？
Isn't she afraid that I will know?
她就不怕我知道吗？
Do I need to know that I can't rush her?
我需要知道我不能催促她吗？
So she said she bought it at the train station
所以她说她是在火车站买的
I didn't expect it would cause such a big deal.
没想到会引起这么大的事情。
Do you believe it
你相信吗
I said
我说
Do you believe she doesn’t like that guy?
你相信她不喜欢那个男人吗？
I
我
Believe it
相信它
you hesitated
你犹豫了
Let me tell you in this day and age
让我告诉你在这个时代
Women can be very wild
女人可以很狂野
You experience it firsthand
你亲身体验
Anyway, where is the woman?
无论如何，那个女人在哪里？
I won't believe it
我不会相信
I trust my wife anyway
无论如何我相信我的妻子
These two swords of mine have been traveling around the world for decades.
我的这两把剑几十年来一直在世界各地旅行。
Do not kill unknown people with the sword
不要用剑杀死不明的人
I really didn't expect that
我真的没想到
I will actually use it to cut grass and feed horses one day.
有一天我实际上会用它来割草和喂马。
I'm Zhao An
我是赵安
How can I accept the humiliation here?
我怎么能接受这里的屈辱呢？
God wants to kill me
神想要杀了我
I must defy heaven
我必须反抗天堂
You two have worked hard with me.
你们两个和我一起努力了。
I'm going to die
我就要死了
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
team leader
队长
What's wrong
怎么了
This horse has such a strong temper
这马脾气这么大
Kicked me in the ass
踢了我的屁股
Got kicked
被踢了
you you
你你
Why are you so stupid?
你怎么这么傻？
what can you do
你能做什么
Let me do it
让我来做吧
Be careful
当心
Brother, what's wrong with you?
兄弟，你怎么了？
Brother you
兄弟你
Why are you so careless?
你怎么这么不小心呢？
rolling
滚动
That's easy to say
这很容易说
If you can, go and wipe the horse's body.
如果可以的话，去给马擦身子吧。
I'll go, I'll go
我去我去
Optimistic
乐观的
wait
等待
put the knife down
把刀放下
this horse
这匹马
If a hair falls out
如果一根头发脱落
I want it
我要它
I want you to kill me
我要你杀了我
Optimistic
乐观的
team leader
队长
No need for him to yell
不需要他大喊大叫
drink water drink water
喝水喝水
Wait for him to come out
等他出来
Where was the kick?
踢哪儿了？
you kick him
你踢他
Don't hold it back
不要阻止它
good horse
好马
What a good horse
多么好的一匹马
Do you think he was fooled by the horse?
你认为他被马愚弄了吗？
Kicked in the head, kicked in the temple
头部被踢，太阳穴被踢
Xiaodouzi
Xiaodouzi
This is the name I gave it
这是我给它起的名字
is that useful
有那么有用吗
Chief Kimura named it Takeda Shingen
木村队长将其命名为武田信玄
You call me Xiaodouzi
You call me Xiaodouzi
soybeans
大豆
elder brother
哥哥
You call it Takeda Shingen
你叫武田信玄
See if it answers or not
看看有没有回复
Takeda Shingen
武田信玄
Xiaodouzi
Xiaodouzi
No trouble, no trouble
没有麻烦，没有麻烦
Since the horse is so good to you
既然马对你这么好
starting today
从今天开始
You give the horse a bath
你给马洗澡
OK
好的
no problem
没问题
trunk
树干
We have
我们有
new tasks
新任务
team leader
队长
What new tasks do we have?
我们有哪些新任务？
Transport feed
运输饲料
interesting
有趣的
ten little indians
十个小印第安人
One person choked to death, and there were nine left.
1人窒息死亡，目前还剩9人。
Nine little Indians sleep on one side
九个小印第安人睡在一侧
One woke up and there were eight left
一个醒来，还剩下八个
Hello Mr. Zhu
Hello Mr. Zhu
Hello
你好
I don’t know Mr. Zhu
我不认识朱先生
Is there any important information you want to tell me?
您有什么重要信息想告诉我吗？
Is such that
是这样的吗
I worked at J.P. Morgan Bank
我曾在摩根大通银行工作
Research money printing technology
研究印钞技术
A colleague of mine is a bronze sculptor
我的一位同事是一位青铜雕塑家
Later we returned to China together
后来我们一起回到中国
One day more than three months ago
三个多月前的一天
He gave me a call
他给我打电话
explain
解释
Suspecting that I am being followed
怀疑我被跟踪
We lost contact after that
之后我们就失去了联系
until recently
直到最近
One day he suddenly found me
有一天他突然找到我
Said he was kidnapped
说自己被绑架了
Imprisoned in an underground factory
被关进地下工厂
Forced to participate in counterfeiting legal tender
被迫参与造假法定货币
Later he developed acute appendicitis
后来患上了急性阑尾炎
Sent to hospital for treatment
被送往医院救治
Only then did I find a chance to escape
这时候我才找到逃跑的机会
He asked me to help him leave Shanghai
他让我帮他离开上海
and warned me that
并警告我
Those people are also asking about my whereabouts
那些人也在询问我的行踪
Want me to be on guard
想要我保持警惕
I bought the ticket for him
我给他买了票
come home
回家
But he disappeared
但他却消失了
The house is a mess
房子乱七八糟
obviously
明显地
The gang found him again
团伙又找到了他
and kidnapped him
并绑架了他
Then I found out I was being followed
然后我发现我被跟踪了
He was almost kidnapped
他差点被绑架
I moved to the French Concession
我搬到了法租界
Capture him
抓住他
Do you know who he is?
你知道他是谁吗？
Special agent of the Military Section of the Japanese Army Ministry
日本陆军省军事科特务员
Where is that underground factory?
那个地下工厂在哪里？
have no idea
不知道
He said he was kidnapped
他说他被绑架了
and on the way to the hospital
在去医院的路上
blindfolded
蒙住眼睛
That car also drove around on purpose.
那辆车还故意到处乱跑。
He cannot judge the distance of a place
他无法判断一个地方的距离
I only know it's underground
我只知道是在地下
No sunshine all day long
整天没有阳光
Work, food and accommodation
工作、饮食和住宿
It's all there
一切都在那里
How many people are there in total in this factory?
这家工厂一共有多少人？
There must be dozens of people
应该有几十人
Some do printing
有的做印刷
Making plates
制作板材
Making bronze sculptures
制作青铜雕塑
Technical
技术的
The equipment is also very complete
设备也很齐全
Most of these people were kidnapped.
这些人大部分都被绑架了。
As long as you don't cooperate at work
只要你不配合工作
Or you are incompetent at work
或者你在工作上不胜任
will be executed
将被处决
He witnessed three people being executed on the spot
他目睹了三人被当场处决
In fact, my colleague
事实上，我的同事
He knows a little Japanese
他懂一点日语
Once he overheard their conversation
有一次他无意中听到了他们的谈话
Talk about this operation of printing counterfeit banknotes
说说印制假钞的这次操作
called cedar plan
称为雪松计划
cedar plan
雪松计划
I heard that in addition to legal currency
听说除了法币
The Japanese are still trying to fake it
日本人还在试图伪造它
Border currency issued by the CCP’s border areas
中共边境地区发行的边境货币
Once counterfeit legal currency becomes widespread
一旦假冒法币泛滥
Not only the Chongqing government’s economic
不仅是重庆市政府的经济
will be severely hit
将会受到严重打击
Even the people in the Kuomintang-controlled areas
就连国统区的人民
Life will be even worse
生活将会更加糟糕
Strange
奇怪的
Why don't you say it doesn't kick two knives?
为什么不说它不踢两刀？
We have a good relationship
我们关系很好
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
Does it still hurt you?
它还伤害你吗？
I'll kick you, try it
我踢你，你试试
elder brother
哥哥
Don't shoot bro
别开枪兄弟
Turn around
回转
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
It's okay if you don't talk
如果你不说话也没关系
elder brother
哥哥
Calm down bro
冷静点兄弟
stop
停止
what do you do
你做什么工作
us
我们
We are from a horse farm
我们来自马场
Come and pull the feed
过来拉饲料
Why did he call you Captain Zhao?
他为什么叫你赵队长？
The racecourse is divided into several teams
赛马场分为多个队伍
I'm the captain of the feed team
我是饲料队队长
Keep doing your work
继续做好你的工作
Does anyone have any questions?
有人有任何疑问吗？
Don't tell me here
别在这里告诉我
yes
是的
Don't worry, we're just here to do the work.
别担心，我们只是来完成工作的。
brother
兄弟
Have you ever seen someone wearing a brown coat?
你见过有人穿着棕色外套吗？
People with injuries on their hands
手上有伤的人
No
不
we have been working
我们一直在工作
I didn't see anyone passing by
我没看到有人路过
Thanks
谢谢
elder brother
哥哥
you betrayed me
你背叛了我
I don't
我不
I just said I didn't see anyone
我只是说我没看到任何人
Shoot
射击
put the gun down
把枪放下
lay down
躺下
Been chasing me for more than half a month
追了我半个多月了
When crossing the Pinghan-Han Railway
穿越平汉铁路时
I almost died in your hands
我差点死在你手里
you traitor
你这个叛徒
you guys
你们
Just too merciful
简直太仁慈了
Nothing big can happen
不会有什么大事发生
Shoot
射击
kill me
杀了我
You can't escape either
你也无法逃脱
Who are they?
他们是谁？
Anti-Japanese elements
抗日分子
Should we take them back?
我们应该把它们带回来吗？
Injured brother
受伤的兄弟
sorry
对不起
elder brother
哥哥
I almost got you in trouble
我差点给你惹上麻烦
We're fine
我们很好
You're seriously injured
你受了重伤
Still bleeding
还在流血
The bullet is still inside
子弹还在里面
I need to go to the hospital.
我需要去医院。
I can't go to the hospital
我不能去医院
Are you from Chongqing or Yan'an?
你是重庆人还是延安人？
I'm just a Chinese
我只是一个中国人
I asked a little too much
我问得有点太多了
We are also Chinese
我们也是中国人
trunk
树干
Isn't your cousin in a private clinic?
你表弟不是在私人诊所吗？
right
正确的
My cousin is very skilled in medicine
我的表弟医术很高明
Can help you take out the bullet
可以帮你取出子弹
right
正确的
Do not bother
不打扰
Get the stool quickly
赶紧去拿凳子
elder brother
哥哥
Hurry up
赶快
sit
坐
you saved our lives
你救了我们的命
We learned that a favor was repaid
我们得知有恩必报
You are hurt so badly now
你现在伤得很重
If you don't have surgery, your life will be gone.
如果不做手术，你的生命就会消失。
real
真实的
Is it far
远吗
Far but not far
远但不远
But I don’t want to tell my cousin first.
但我不想先告诉我表弟。
I think it works
我认为它有效
You go to your cousin first
你先去找你表弟
Let him send the other patients away first
让他先把其他病人送走
What do you call me brother?
你叫我什么兄弟？
Call me Lao Tian
请叫我老田
Brother Tian
田哥
You call me Xiao Zhao
你叫我小赵吧
His name is Trunk
他的名字叫特兰克
You have difficulty moving now
您现在行动困难
Take my carriage
乘坐我的马车
I pull you over slowly
我慢慢把你拉过来
trunk
树干
You go now
你现在走
Go to your brother's place
去你哥哥那儿
Arrangements have been made to come and greet us.
已经安排好来迎接我们了。
OK
好的
Brother Tian
田哥
Believe me
相信我
But
但
Is there anyone who loves him more than me?
还有人比我更爱他吗？
how long have you been together
你们在一起多久了
do you love him very much
你很爱他吗
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
you
你
But haven't you already
但你不是已经
terribly sorry
非常抱歉
Shouldn't appear like this
不应该出现这样的情况
No
不
I'm the one who should be sorry
我才是最应该抱歉的人
I'm glad that Mr. Yamashita is still alive.
我很高兴山下先生还活着。
But I just behaved
但我只是表现
But so rude
但如此粗鲁
do you know
你知道吗
when people are dying
当人们即将死去时
Will see myself without the body
会看到没有身体的自己
that moment
那一刻
I really saw myself
我真的看到了自己
if i can survive
如果我能活下来
I must start over
我必须重新开始
My life
我的生活
You must have been seriously injured at the time
你当时一定受了重伤
Two-thirds of my lung was removed
我的三分之二的肺被切除了
I can no longer be a soldier
我不能再当兵了
So Mr. Yamashita is now
所以现在山下先生
I am an ordinary businessman now
我现在是一个普通的商人
i love movies
我喜欢电影
This beautiful flower moon
这美丽的花月
This is the first movie I invested in
这是我投资的第一部电影
Ms. Hanlu joins the team
韩璐女士加入团队
I believe
我相信
will be a great success
将会取得巨大的成功
It turns out that you invested in this movie
原来你投资了这部电影
No wonder it looks like willow
难怪看起来像柳树
Big stars like Chen Juanjuan
Big stars like Chen Juanjuan
Everyone is willing to play some small roles
每个人都愿意扮演一些小角色
Compared with Miss Hanlu
与韩璐小姐相比
They are only suitable for small roles
他们只适合演小角色
where
在哪里
My career has stalled for the most part
我的职业生涯大部分时间都停滞不前
The audience almost forgot about me
观众差点忘了我
but
但
i will never forget you
我永远不会忘记你
but I
但是我
Mr. Yamashita
山下先生
I think you should also know
我想你也应该知道
I already feel like I belong
我已经感觉到我有归属感
you mean
你的意思是
Mr. Jiang
Mr. Jiang
Although I do
虽然我这样做
It’s not what a gentleman does
这不是绅士该做的事
But I really can't bear it
但我真的无法忍受
See Miss Hanlu again
再次见到韩璐小姐
be deceived again
再次被骗
My sincerity has been let down again
我的诚意又被辜负了
I believe in tomorrow's drama
我相信明天的戏剧
will be more exciting
将会更加精彩
That
那
I'll take my leave first
我先告辞了
How's the injury?
伤势如何？
Fortunately, no artery was injured.
幸运的是，没有伤到动脉。
Arrange surgery as soon as possible
尽快安排手术
good
好的
Brother Tian
田哥
Here is Dr. Han
这里是韩博士
rest assured
放心
Have you explained everything?
你解释清楚一切了吗？
Don't worry, I've explained it.
别担心，我已经解释过了。
Doctor Han is our informant
韩医生是我们的线人
absolutely reliable
绝对可靠
team leader
队长
Who is this Lao Tian?
这个老田是谁？
of the Chinese Communist Party
中国共产党的
How did you know
你怎么知道
Do you remember the man in the coffee coat?
你还记得那个穿咖啡大衣的男人吗？
Say to Lao Tian
对老田说
When passing the Pinghan Railway
经过平汉铁路时
I almost died at the hands of Lao Tian
我差点死在老田手里
Maybe they came from Yan'an
也许他们来自延安
The Pinghan-Hankou Railway is the only way to go
平汉铁路是必经之路
Makes sense
说得通
Nao Tian said that the coffee jacket is a traitor
闹天说咖啡外套是叛徒
what's going on
这是怎么回事
I guess it’s an internal campaign by the Chinese Communist Party.
我猜这是中国共产党的内部运动。
Chased all the way here
一路追到这里
Then why don't we
那我们为什么不
Just take him back for interrogation.
把他带回去审问就行了。
Can you please give me some ideas?
你能给我一些想法吗？
The CCP has extremely hidden communication lines in Shanghai
中共在上海有极其隐蔽的通讯线路
Lao Tian is injured now
老田现在受伤了
He let the traitor escape again
他又让叛徒逃走了
He will definitely contact their people
他一定会联系他们的人
We must not alert the enemy
我们不能惊动敌人
Zhangji trap setting
Zhangji trap setting
Only then can we defeat the Hulao Dragon
只有这样，我们才能打败虎牢龙
Understood
明白了
Walk
走
team leader
队长
Slow down
减速
This person's name is Magpie
这个人的名字叫喜鹊
He's a lurker we planted in Yan'an
他是我们在延安安插的潜伏者
Recently arrived in Shanghai
近日抵达上海
But his whereabouts are unknown
但他的下落不明
Gotta find him
一定要找到他
Why are we in Yan'an?
我们为什么在延安？
Place latent personnel
安置潜伏人员
Don't ask so many questions
别问那么多问题
Don't ask anything
不要问任何事
There must be many ulterior conspiracies.
其中必定有许多不可告人的阴谋。
What did you say
你说什么
nothing
没有什么
Also
还
Just a clue
只是一个线索
He has a lover in Shanghai
他在上海有一个情人
Called Cai Hongling
叫蔡红菱
She's a dancer at Xian Lesi Ballroom
她是西安乐思舞厅的舞者
You have to find a way to get to her
你必须想办法接近她
What is the purpose of looking for magpies?
寻找喜鹊的目的是什么？
He has something important in his hand
他手里拿着很重要的东西
what
什么
Hello
你好
Mr. Chen
陈先生
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
hello
你好
I called just to ask.
我打电话只是想问问。
Is Mr. Chen free tomorrow morning?
陈先生明天早上有空吗？
should have
应该有
What's up
这是怎么回事
some things
有些事情
I would like to ask Mr. Chen for a favor
我想请陈先生帮个忙
Is it about the fan association again?
又是粉丝协会的事吗？
Roughly the same
大致相同
OK
好的
So where shall we meet?
那么我们在哪里见面呢？
You can come directly to my house
你可以直接来我家
Go to Miss Hanlu’s house
去韩露小姐家
You won't be photographed by tabloid reporters, right?
你不会被小报记者拍照吧？
Then I can't explain it to my wife.
那我就没法跟老婆解释了。
can you come
你能来么
I feel relieved
我感到轻松多了
some things
有些事情
I don't want someone I hate to do it.
我不想让我讨厌的人这么做。
Miss Hanlu's voice
韩璐小姐的声音
It sounds a little hoarse
听起来有点沙哑
Maybe I've been too tired recently
也许我最近太累了
That's settled
就这样解决了
tomorrow morning
明天早上
I will definitely be at home
我一定会在家
good
好的
See you or leave
再见或离开
some things
有些事情
I don't want someone I hate to do it.
我不想让我讨厌的人这么做。
tomorrow morning
明天早上
I will definitely be at home
我一定会在家
why did she say that
她为什么这么说
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
I’m off duty
我下班了
Don’t you know I’m number 76?
你不知道我是76号吗？
Tell me to get off work
告诉我下班了
correct
正确的
recently
最近
Do you have any suspicious people here?
你们这里有可疑的人吗？
No
不
valuable information now
现在有价值的信息
The reward is double
奖励是双倍的
You, the informants, are the most profitable now.
你们这些线人，现在是最赚钱的。
I don’t even want to do it anymore
我什至不想再这样做了
You can be an informant
你可以成为一名线人
Captain Zhao?
Captain Zhao?
That old Tian seems to be suspicious.
那老田似乎有些疑惑。
what happened
发生了什么
Where is he now?
他现在在哪儿？
Still upstairs
还在楼上
You stabilize him first
你先稳定住他
I'll be here in a minute
我一会儿就到
good
好的
wait
等待
Notify the gendarmerie
通知宪兵队
Why
为什么
Leave it alone
不要管它
I asked you to notify the gendarmerie
我请你通知宪兵队
yes
是的
Laotian
老挝语
Who is it?
是谁？
play high
玩得高
Is something wrong at this late hour?
这么晚了，是不是有什么事？
I'm here to say goodbye to you
我是来跟你告别的
Say goodbye
说再见
Come in and talk
进来谈谈
Been here before
以前来过这里
First time here
第一次来这里
you want to ask me
你想问我
How do you know you live here?
你怎么知道你住在这里？
I didn’t know until you came, too.
我也不知道，直到你也来了。
Where is Chen Jiaping?
陈家平在哪里？
Not at home?
不在家？
Working overtime
加班
Coming back soon
即将回来
you sit
你坐
We don’t have any coffee powder at home
我们家里没有咖啡粉
Let me get you a cup of tea
让我给你倒杯茶
no, I'm fine
不我没事
I'll leave after saying a few words to you
跟你说了几句话我就走了
I'm leaving Taihe Trading Company
我要离开泰和商贸公司
Why
为什么
in Shanghai
在上海
There's a reclusive British communications expert
有一位隐居的英国通讯专家
Eisen Meyer
艾森·迈耶
I visited him some time ago
我前段时间拜访过他
He quite appreciates me
他很欣赏我
And he promised
并且他答应了
If I stop doing things for the Japanese
如果我不再为日本人做事
He accepted me as his disciple
他收我为徒
The salary level and everything are pretty good.
工资水平什么的都还不错。
I'm quite interested
我很感兴趣
But our business
但我们的生意
You can't leave if you want to, right?
你想走就走不了，对吗？
I submitted my application
我提交了申请
I want to go back and take care of my seriously ill grandma
我要回去照顾病重的奶奶
And I deliberately in my recent work
而我在最近的工作中刻意
Showing no results
没有显示结果
Make mistakes frequently
经常犯错误
They probably think I'm a loser
他们可能认为我是个失败者
Of no use
没用的
For this reason
为此原因
Can they let you go easily?
他们能轻易放你走吗？
The nature of my job
我的工作性质
It stands to reason that it's not that easy
按理说没那么容易
but you know
但你知道
People want to leave
人们想要离开
Who can keep it?
谁能保留它？
And I checked it up and down
我上下检查了一遍
There was some blood
有一些血
These days
这些日子
Nothing can be done without spending money
不花钱什么都做不了
Actually
实际上
I already thought that place was not suitable for you
我已经认为那个地方不适合你
fine
美好的
Learn techniques from British experts
向英国专家学习技术
happy for you
为你感到高兴
I also look forward to seeing a better you
我也期待见到更好的你
Thanks
谢谢
otherwise
否则
Let me be your brother
让我成为你的兄弟
Okay
好的
Such an excellent brother
这么优秀的哥哥
Who does not like
谁不喜欢
OK
好的
Then we've settled
然后我们就解决了
Sister, I'm leaving
姐姐我走了
How can I contact you in the future?
以后怎么联系你？
rest assured
放心
I won't go too far
我不会走得太远
I still want to protect you
我仍然想保护你
By the way, sister
顺便说一句，姐姐
That's it
就是这样
Search
搜索
gendarmerie
宪兵队
He just called the gendarmerie
他刚刚给宪兵队打电话
you killed their people
你杀了他们的人
They won't let you go
他们不会让你走
You go quickly
你快走
leave me alone
请别打扰我
Brother Tian
田哥
I brought you here
我带你来这里
Almost killed you
差点杀了你
If I leave by myself
如果我一个人离开
Am I still Chinese?
我还是中国人吗？
Walk
走
Search
搜索
Leave the scene to other departments for investigation
现场交由其他部门调查
Walk
走
Brother Tian
田哥
Come and stay at my house tonight
今晚来我家住下吧
No more
不再
I can't trouble you anymore
我不能再麻烦你了
I know something like this happened
我知道发生了这样的事情
You won't believe me
你不会相信我
I'm just worried
我只是担心
You are very weak now
你现在很虚弱
You are familiar with this place
你对这个地方很熟悉
Can you help me find a hotel first?
你能先帮我找个酒店吗？
Let's talk about staying here
我们来谈谈住在这里的事
no problem
没问题
Jiaping
Jiaping
you're awake
你醒了
You stayed with me all night
你陪我度过了一夜
I'm thinking
我在想
if you wake up
如果你醒来
Found no one there
发现那里没有人
in this empty room
在这个空荡荡的房间里
Then I really don’t know
那我真的不知道了
Is it heaven or earth?
是天上还是人间？
I wish this was heaven
我希望这是天堂
But I don’t want you here
但我不想让你在这里
Then don't you think
那你不觉得
no matter it's me
不管是我
still you
还是你
Shouldn't they all be here?
他们不应该都在这里吗？
You must think I'm stupid, right?
你一定觉得我很蠢吧？
Actually
实际上
There are many ups and downs in life
人生有很多坎坷
Some hurdles are really difficult to pass
有些坎确实很难跨过
But in this way you
但通过这种方式你
I went through this hurdle personally.
我个人经历了这个障碍。
Although it's a bit more tragic
虽然比较悲惨一些
But it's worth it
但这是值得的
Why don't you go back quickly?
你为什么不快点回去呢？
If the man I love leaves me
如果我爱的人离开我
But he stayed out all night with another woman
但他和另一个女人在外面过夜
I have to kill him
我必须杀了他
Then do you think she won't do this?
那你觉得她不会这么做吗？
Even though you say so
虽然你这么说
But actually I know you love each other very much
但其实我知道你们非常相爱
I really envy you
我真的很羡慕你
It's so quiet now
现在是如此安静
Just like the silence before the war broke out
就像战争爆发前的寂静一样
Next
下一个
I have to face the swarm of reporters
我要面对蜂拥而至的记者
Take me as the director who asked
就当我是问的导演吧
Producer
制片人
movie studio owner
电影制片厂老板
When I think of these
当我想到这些的时候
Might as well continue to stay here
还不如继续留在这里
That
那
Just think about one more thing
再想一件事
I still have to face my lovely wife
我还要面对我可爱的妻子
I have a feeling you'll be fine
我有预感你会没事的
Go back quickly
赶紧回去吧
I won't do stupid things again
我不会再做傻事了
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
as you would expect
正如你所期望的
Lao Tian changed to a hotel early in the morning
老田一早就换了酒店
Are you tracking?
你在追踪吗？
Followed
已关注
He moved to the Chang Lai Hotel three streets away.
他搬到了三条街外的昌莱酒店。
team leader
队长
You said you went through so much effort to save him yesterday
你说昨天你费了好大的力气才救了他
Why does he still not trust you?
为什么他还是不信任你？
I didn't save him just to make him believe in me.
我救他并不是为了让他相信我。
Even if he believes me
就算他相信我
He won't let me know his whereabouts
他不会让我知道他的行踪
I know the people of the CCP very well
我很了解中共人民
Very cunning
非常狡猾
Then why are we saving him?
那我们为什么要救他？
Follow the clues
跟随线索
Doctor Han is dead now
韩医生现已去世
The clues to find him are gone
寻找他的线索已经消失
Then he will think that the danger has been removed
然后他就会认为危险已经解除了
Will wait for the opportunity
会等待机会
Then I'll arrange someone
那我就安排人
Follow him every step of the way
跟随他的每一步
remember
记住
follow him
跟着他
Have to change someone every half hour
每半小时就得换一个人
cannot be repeated
不能重复
clear
清除
After my two days of observation and research,
经过我两天的观察和研究，
I discovered that adzuki beans cannot eat leguminous grasses
我发现小豆不能吃豆科草
Look at this shit
看看这个狗屎
Severe indigestion
严重消化不良
I know Xiaodouzi
我认识小豆子
Just feel sick to your stomach
只是感觉胃不舒服
Feeling depressed
心情郁闷
When you feel depressed, life will not be happy.
当你感到沮丧时，生活就不会快乐。
It seems that it is better to eat alfalfa in the future.
看来以后还是吃苜蓿比较好。
I said you really use yourself as a stable driver.
我说你真把自己当稳定司机了。
This is what I call doing what I do and loving what I do.
这就是我所说的做我所做的事情和热爱我所做的事情。
You know shit
你知道屎
team leader
队长
how's it going
怎么样了
There is progress
有进步
Lao Tian went to the newspaper office
老田去了报社
Why go to the newspaper office?
为什么要去报社？
A missing person notice was posted
已张贴失踪人员告示
Dong Lizhen female
Dong Lizhen female
Thirty-seven years old
三十七岁
This is their code for contacting each other.
这是他们相互联系的代码。
right
正确的
But we can't understand
但我们无法理解
It doesn’t matter if you don’t understand
如果你不明白也没关系
Explain Lao Tian
解释老田
Started contacting their people
开始联系他们的人
good thing
好东西
Prepare two clothes
准备两件衣服
I will follow up personally tomorrow
明天我会亲自跟进
yes
是的
elder brother
哥哥
I just heard what you said about Tian Bu Tian.
我刚刚听到你说天不天的事情。
If you can let little beans spread happily in the fields,
如果你能让小豆子在田野里快乐地生长，
run two steps
跑两步
I believe it will be of great benefit.
相信会有很大的好处。
roll
卷
gentlemen
先生们
Is there fire?
有火吗？
What do you smoke?
你抽什么烟？
laodaopai
laodaopai
Made in UK
英国制造
Your lighter is
你的打火机是
Langson diesel lighter
兰森柴油打火机
American man-made
美国人造的
Hello comrade
你好同志
Hello
你好